Guide to the Richard Cardarelli Papers 1969-2005 GLBTQ 2012.09 GLBTQ.2012.09
Connecticut Polish American Archives
- Series I: Subject Files
  - Institute for the Protection of Lesbian and Gay Youth, New York. Includes: Testimonies presented to a the Pennsylvania State Legislature and to the New York State Task Force on Gay Issues, as well as relative correspondence., 1984 - 1985 (Box 6, Folder 21)
  - International AIDS Candlelight Memorial, undated (Box 6, Folder 22)
  - Laffin, Paul T. 1956-1999 [articles, liturgy of Christian Burial] (Box 6, Folder 23)
  - (The) Little Chronicale 2003, Vol. 83, Issue 3 (Box 6, Folder 24)
  - Love Makes a Family (articles, flyers], undated (Box 6, Folder 25)
  - Metropolitan Ccommunity Church, San Francisco, undated (Box 6, Folder 26)
  - Mercy of God Community, undated (Box 6, Folder 27)
  - Mercy of God Community, Brief History, [typescript], 2003 (Box 6, Folder 28)
  - Metroline December 24, 1992 Vol. 15, No. 25 (contains an interview with Richard Cardarelli) (Box 6, Folder 29)
  - Metropolitan Community Church of Hartford, church service, 1997 (Box 6, Folder 30)
  - Military and Gays, [articles, brochures], 1982-1984 (Box 6, Folder 31)
  - Morality of Homosexuality, by Richard Cardarelli, 1971 (Box 6, Folder 32)
  - Most Helpful Articles on Homosexuality, 1979-1993 (Box 6, Folder 33)
  - Names Project, 1988 (Box 7, Folder 1)
  - National AIDS Candle lights March, Washington, D.C., [program], October 12, 1996 (Box 7, Folder 2)
  - National March On Washington For Lesbian & Gay Rights [program, leaflet], October 14, 1979 (Box 7, Folder 3)
  - National March On Washington For Lesbian & Gay Rights, October 11, 1987 (Box 7, Folder 4)
  - National Queer Arts Festival, San Francisco, [program], 2004 (Box 7, Folder 5)
  - New England Notes, Dignity New England periodical, December, 1999 (Box 7, Folder 6)
  - New Ways Ministry, [articles, flyers, letters], 1981-2003, 2005 (Box 7, Folder 7)
  - New Ways Ministry, Conference, 1985 (Box 7, Folder 8)
  - New Ways Ministry, Conference, 1987 (Box 7, Folder 9)
  - New Ways Ministry, Conference, 2002 (Box 7, Folder 10)
  - New Ways Ministry, Conference, 2006-2007 (Box 7, Folder 11)
  - East Bay Dignity Newsletters: August 1986, Vol. IV, No. 4; October 1986, Vol. IV, No. 5; December 1986, Vol. IV, No. 6; February 1987, Vol. V, No. 1; April 1987, Vol. V, No. 2; August 1987, Vol. V, No. 4; October4 1987, Vol. V, No. 5., 1986-1987 (Box 7, Folder 12)
  - Northeast Faerie Register, 2003 (Box 7, Folder 13)
  - Nugent, Robert/Geannine Gramick vs. Vatican, 1999 - (Box 7, Folder 14)
  - One in Christ Jesus? Women and the Future of the Church. St. Joseph's College, March 29, 1993 (Box 7, Folder 15)
  - Order of Saint Mary Magdalene, 1997-1999 (Box 7, Folder 16)
  - Out Awards. Connecticut Coalition for Lesbian, Gay, Bisexual and Transgender Civil Rights, 1999 - (Box 7, Folder 17)
  - Pacific School of Religion, Berkeley, CA, undated (Box 7, Folder 18)
  - Pastoral Care Team Dignity Hartford, 1991 (Box 7, Folder 19)
  - Pilgrimage to the Shrines + Cathedrals of France, 1999 (Box 7, Folder 20)
  - Popes [articles], 2005 (Box 7, Folder 21)
  - Prayers, undated (Box 7, Folder 22)
  - Presbyterian Church: Keeping Body and Soul Together [document for 203rd General Assembly], 1991 (Box 7, Folder 23)
  - Presbyterians, [flyers, brochures, articles], 1995-2000 (Box 7, Folder 24)
  - Priests still die of AIDS as Church postpones needed dialogue, National Catholic Reporter, October 27, 2000 (Box 7, Folder 25)
  - Q Sangha Buddhist Spirituality, San Francisco, undated (Box 7, Folder 26)
  - Queer Nation [articles, songs, liturgical components], 1991-1992 (Box 7, Folder 27)
  - Radical Faeries [flyers, gatherings], 1987-2000 (Box 7, Folder 28)
  - Rainbow Interfaith Covenant and Outreach, undated (Box 7, Folder 29)
  - "Rearticulation of Identities in Dignity; Dignity/Hartford's Sunday Liturgy as an Identity Project"; [Paper by student Kathleen Cassidy with survey], April 19, 1996 (Box 7, Folder 30)
  - "The Role of Spiritual Direction in Gay Ministry" [Paper by Brother Richard Cardarelli, OFM Cap., Maryknoll School of Theology], Spring 1981 (Box 7, Folder 31)
  - Saint Francis Saint Claire Parish, 1994-1995 (Box 7, Folder 32)
  - Saint Francis Saint Claire Parish, 1996-1998 (Box 7, Folder 33)
  - Saint Francis Saint Claire Parish, 1999-2000 (Box 7, Folder 34)
  - Saint Patrick's Day Parade New York Gays [flyers, articles], March 17, 1994 (Box 7, Folder 35)
  - Same Gender Marriage Bill, Connecticut, 2001 (Box 7, Folder 36)
  - San Francisco Gay Pride, 2003 (Box 7, Folder 37)
  - San Francisco Gay Pride, 2004 (Box 7, Folder 38)
  - San Francisco Gay Pride, 2005 (Box 7, Folder 39)
  - San Francisco International Gay & Lesbian Film Festival [program], 2003 (Box 7, Folder 40)
  - Senior Gays & Lesbians [articles, flyers], 1984 (Box 7, Folder 41)
  - Solidarity Sunday, Washington, DC, October 8, 1995 (Box 8, Folder 5)
  - Solidarity Sunday, Washington, October 4, 1998 (Box 8, Folder 6)
  - Soul Force [articles, emails about], 2000 (Box 8, Folder 7)
  - Stonewall, [articles], 1989 (Box 8, Folder 1)
  - Stonewall 25, June 26, 1994 (Box 8, Folder 2)
  - Stonewall [flyer] 30th anniversary, 1999 (Box 8, Folder 3)
  - Stop the Hate, Nov. 1999 (Box 8, Folder 8)
  - TARC, Tenderloin AIDS Resource Center, San Francisco [brochure], undated (Box 8, Folder 9)
  - Tri-State Area Committee on Lesbian/Gay Issues, 1990 (Box 8, Folder 9)
  - True Colors, Sexual minority youth and family services of Conn. Resource Guide, 1999 (Box 8, Folder 10)
  - Vigil in Memory of Matthew Sheppard, October 15, 1998 (Box 8, Folder 11)
  - A Way to the Cross for the Lesbian and Gay Community, by Claudia Windal [copy of article from "The Witness", undated (Box 8, Folder 12)
  - What the Church Teaches about Homosexuality, by Richard Sparks, July 1999 (Box 8, Folder 14)
  - Winter is a drag ball, Burlington, VT [flyer and card], undated (Box 8, Folder 13)
  - Witness Our Welcome (W.O.W.), [Program Book, with materials picked up at the conference], 2000 (Box 8, Folder 15)
  - Shabbat Service: Rabbi Elissa M. Kohen, October 29, 1999 (Box 8, Folder 4)
  - Dignity USA 2009 Convention [program, brochures, liturgies] (Box 8, Folder 16)
  - God is still speaking [Red Binder with conference materials]; The still speaking initiative., March 30, 2004 (Box 8, Object 1)
  - Same Sex Marriage [articles in black binder]; Gay News Group, Yahoo.com and other related blogs, April - June, 2004 (Box 8, Object 2)
  - Gays and the Church [gray binder with scrapbook of newspaper articles] 1985-1987, 1993, 2007 (Box 8, Object 3)
  - Eucharistic Liturgy [white binder with rainbow], April 25th, 1999 (Box 8, Object 4)
- Series II: Photograph Albums, Scrapbooks and other graphic material
  - Connecticut Gay Rights Bill Scrapbook Vol. 1, 1987 (Object Scrapbook of Photographs)
  - Connecticut Gay Rights Bill Scrapbook Vol. II, 1988-1990 (Object Scrapbook of Photographs)
  - Connecticut Gay Rights Bill Scrapbook Vol. III, 1990-1991 (Object Scrapbook of Photographs)
  - Connecticut Gay Rights Bill Scrapbook Vol. IV, 1991-1994 (Object Scrapbook of Photographs)
  - Dignity Convention 1989 (Object Scrapbook of Photographs)
  - Dignity Conventions 1991, 1993, 1995 (Object Scrapbook of Photographs)
  - Dignity Conventions Los Angeles 1995 (Object Scrapbook of Photographs)
  - Dignity Conventions 1997, 1999, 2001, 2002, 2005, 1997-2005 (Object Scrapbook of Photographs)
  - Dignity Hartford Scrapbook Vol. 1, 1975-1989 (Object Scrapbook of Photographs)
  - Dignity Hartford Scrapbook Vol. II, 1987-1988 (Object Scrapbook of Photographs)
  - Dignity Hartford Scrapbook Vol. III, 1989-1990 (Object Scrapbook of Photographs)
  - Dignity Hartford Scrapbook Vol. IV, 1990-1991 (Object Scrapbook of Photographs)
  - Dignity Hartford Scrapbook Vol. V, 1991 (Object Scrapbook of Photographs)
  - Dignity Hartford Scrapbook Vol. VI, 1992 - 1993 (Object Scrapbook of Photographs)
  - Dignity Hartford Scrapbook Vol. VII, 1993 - 1994 (Object Scrapbook of Photographs)
  - Dignity Hartford Scrapbook Vol. VIII, 1994-1996 (Object Scrapbook of Photographs)
  - Dignity Hartford Scrapbook Vol. IX, 1996-1998 (Object Scrapbook of Photographs)
  - Dignity Hartford Scrapbook Vol. X, 1998 - 1999 (Object Scrapbook of Photographs)
  - Dignity Hartford Scrapbook Vol. XI, 1999-2000 (Object Scrapbook of Photographs)
  - Dignity Hartford Scrapbook Vol. XII, 2000 (Object Scrapbook of Photographs)
  - Dignity Hartford Scrapbook Vol. XIII, Nov. 10, 2000 - Aug. 25, 2001 (Object Scrapbook of Photographs)
  - Dignity Hartford Scrapbook Vol. XIV part 1, October 2001- November 2002 (Object Scrapbook of Photographs)
  - Dignity Hartford Scrapbook Vol. XIV part 2, May 2002 - April 2003 (Object Scrapbook of Photographs)
  - Dignity Hartford Scrapbook Vol. XV, April 2003 - March 2005 (Object Scrapbook of Photographs)
  - Drag Show Community Center, 1990 St. Patrick's Parade, NYC, 1990 Northhampton Gay Pride Parade, 1994 [Scrapbook] (Object Scrapbook of Photographs)
  - Gay Business Expo [Scrapbook], 1994-1996 (Object Scrapbook of Photographs)
  - Gay Pride, Connecticut and New York [scrapbook] 1969-1989 (Object Scrapbook of Photographs and Articles)
  - Gay Pride, Connecticut and New York [scrapbook] 1989-1993 (Object Scrapbook of Photographs and Articles)
  - Gay Pride, Connecticut and New York [scrapbook] 1993-1996 (Object Scrapbook of Photographs and Articles)
  - Gay Pride, Connecticut and New York [scrapbook] 1997 - 2000 (Object Scrapbook of Photographs and Articles)
  - Hartford Gay Pride [scrapbook] 1997-2003 (Object Scrapbook of Photographs)
  - New York Gay Pride [scrapbook], 1989-1997 (Object Scrapbook of Photographs and Articles)
  - New York Gay Pride [scrapbook], 1998-2002 (Object Scrapbook of Photographs and Articles)
  - Marches on Washington [scrapbook], 1993-2000 (Object Scrapbook of Photographs and Articles)
  - Queer Nation [scrapbook], 1991 (Object Scrapbook of Photographs and Articles)
  - Radical Faeries [scrapbook] vol. I, undated (Object Scrapbook of Photographs and Articles)
  - Radical Faeries [scrapbook] Vol. II, undated (Object Scrapbook of Photographs and Articles)
  - Radical Faeries [scrapbook], undated (Object Scrapbook of Photographs and Articles)
  - Sisters of Perpetual Indulgence [scrapbook], April, 2004 (Object Scrapbook of Photographs and Articles)
  - Same-Sex Marriage [scrapbook of photographs] Feb. 14, March 11, May 17, June-July 5, 2004, 2003 (Object Scrapbook of Photographs)
  - Same-Sex Marriage [scrapbook of articles], Jan 2003- April 2003
  - Same-Sex Marriage [scrapbook of articles], Feb. 2004
  - Same-Sex Marriage [scrapbook of articles], Feb - March 2004
  - Same-Sex Marriage [scrapbook of articles], March 2004
  - Same-Sex Marriage [scrapbook of articles], April 2004 - May 27 2004
  - Same-Sex Marriage [scrapbook of articles], June 3, 2004 - August 19, 2004
  - Same-Sex Marriage [scrapbook of articles], August - December 2004
  - Same-Sex Marriage [scrapbook of articles], January - April 2005
  - Same-Sex Marriage [scrapbook of articles], May - October 2005
  - Same Sex Marriage Connecticut [scrapbook of articles], 2002-2003
  - San Francisco Gay Pride Day [scrapbook of articles], 2004-2005
  - Witness for Disarmament [scrapbook of photos and articles], August 1985 - January 1988
  - Witness for Disarmament [scrapbook of photos and articles], Lent 1987 - January 1988
  - Witness for Disarmament [scrapbook of photos and articles], Lent 1988 - September 1988
  - Witness for Disarmament [scrapbook of photos and articles], October 1988 - December 1989
  - Witness for Disarmament [scrapbook of photos and articles], January 1990 - August 1990
  - Witness for Disarmament [scrapbook of photos and articles], August 1990 - 1997
  - Dignity San Francisco [scrapbook of photos and articles], July 2003-April 2006
  - Dignity San Francisco [scrapbook of photos and articles], June 2006 - August 2007
  - Dignity San Francisco [scrapbook of photos and articles], September 2007 - June 2009
  - Dignity Providence [scrapbook of photos and articles], June 17, 1974 - December 31, 1979
  - Charter of Dignity Hartford [signed, undated, in frame] (Box 11, Object 4)
  - Dignity/Hartford Deceased Members plaque for 30th anniversary, May 22, 2005 (Box 9, Object 3)
  - Folder of Malcolm Boyd entitled "Christmas Thoughts: A Cry From the Underground Church" [scrapbook with article dated 1968] (Box 11, Object 2)
  - AIDS Walk San Francisco 2003, July 20, 2003 (Box 11, Object 1)
  - Funeral photographs of Richard Cardarelli, 2012 (Box 11, Folder 3)
  - Photos of his profession [Cardarelli], November 2004 (Box 11, Folder 2)
  - March on Washington, 1987 [photos] (Box 11, Folder 1)
  - Framed photograph, undated (Box 11, Object 9)
  - Framed photograph, undated (Box 11, Object 11)
  - Framed photograph, undated (Box 11, Object 10)
  - Framed photograph, undated (Box 11, Object 8)
  - Framed photograph, undated (Box 11, Object 5)
  - Framed photograph, undated (Box 11, Object 7)
  - Framed photograph, undated (Box 11, Object 6)
  - "Northampton Gay Pride" [CVS envelope with photos and negatives], 2000 (Box 11, Object 15)
  - "Northampton Gay Pride" CVS envelope with photos and negatives, May 6, 2001 (Box 11, Object 14)
  - "Northhampton Gay Pride" [Ritz Camera box with photos and negatives], undated (Box 11, Object 13)
  - Hartford Gay Pride [small album of photos, untitled, undated] (Box 11, Object 12)
  - Loose scrapbook page with six photographs of people at an exhibit, after 1999 (Box 11, Object 17)
- Series III: Videotapes, Audio cassette
  - Church and Dignity/AIDS, Donahue Show; Gay Bashing, Oprah. VHS, Late 1980's (Box 10, Object 6)
  - Church and Dignity/AIDS, Donahue Show; Gay Bashing, Oprah. DVD, Late 1980's (Box 10, Object 7)
  - Voices in the wilderness [video recording]: gay history: Richard Cardarelli interviews Richard Nelson about an exhibit presented at the Hartford Public Library in 1999. DVD (Box 10, Object 1)
  - Voices in the wilderness [video recording]: gay history: Richard Cardarelli interviews Richard Nelson about an exhibit presented at the Hartford Public Library in 1999. DVD (Box 10, Object 2)
  - Gay Clergy, Sally Jesse Raphael Show, VHS, 1988 (Box 10, Object 4)
  - Gay Clergy, Sally Jesse Raphael Show, DVD, 1988 (Box 10, Object 3)
  - Phil Donahue Show, with Bob Arpin. Also Sally Jesse Raphael Show with Bob Arpin. [VHS], 1988, 1993 (Box 10, Object 8)
  - Phil Donahue Show, with Bob Arpin. Also Sally Jesse Raphael Show with Bob Arpin. [DVD], 1988, 1993 (Box 10, Object 9)
  - Jim Hurley on AIDS, [VHS], undated (Box 10, Object 10)
  - Jim Hurley on AIDS, [DVD], undated (Box 10, Object 11)
  - We Believe with Father John Gatzak [VHS], April 2, 1989 (Box 10, Object 12)
  - We Believe with Father John Gatzak [DVD], April 2, 1989 (Box 10, Object 5)
  - "Defamation" Narrated by Harvey Fierstein for the Gay and Lesbian Alliance Against Defamation, undated (Box 11, Object 16)
- Series IV: Realia
  - Through Truth to Freedom [Realia associated with Dignity USA convention in Philadelphia, 2005] includes button, ID Badge and bag. (Box 8, Object 5, 6, and 7)
  - Fulton Street Fair [ID Badge], 2004 (Box 8, Object 8a and 8b)
  - Canvas Bag with Peace and Pride symbols, undated (Box 8, Object 9)
  - Dignity Envelope with printed art work, undated (Box 8, Object 10)
  - Hand-made glass plaque from the Coalition for Lesbian and Gay Civil Rights and the Connecticut Civil Liberties Union for Contributions to the Community [undated, no name] (Box 8, Object 11)
  - President's Award presented to Dignity/Hartford from Dignity USA (with folder), July 9, 2000 (Box 8, Object 12a and 12b)
  - Sacramentary [book], 1982 (Box 9, Object 1)
  - Lectionary [book], 1982 (Box 9, Object 2)
  - Small white bust of Mary with beads, undated (Box 9, Object 3)
  - Sts. Perpetua and Felicity [small graphic on board; wall hanging], undated (Box 9, Object 4)
  - Mary with baby Jesus [small graphic on board; wall hanging], undated (Box 9, Object 5)
  - Priest's stole [names written on colored ribbons are pinned to the stole], undated (Box 9, Object 6)
  - T-Shirts, 1980-2000 (Box 12)
    - Dignity T-Shirts, 1985-1999 (Box 12)
      - Dignity/Providence Hope (front), n.d, Do It With Dignity (back), undated (Box 12)
      - Dignity We're Here For Good, n.d., undated (Box 12)
      - No Turning Back: Lead Us On O Lord, 1985 (Box 12)
      - Seventh Biennial Dignity Convention, August 22-25, 1985
      - New York Many Lifts One Spirits, Dignity USA, 1991, [Washington, DC]
      - 25th Anniversary Dignity USA Convention, 1995 [Los Angeles]
      - We Are Called Prophets to the World, 1997
      - Dignity USA Convention, Boston, 1997
      - Dignity New York (front), 1999
      - Dignity USA & Stonewall, 1969-1999 30 years of faith and activism (back)
      - USA Gay, Lesbian, Bisexual & Transgender, 2000
      - Catholics New York Chapter [June 2000]
    - Connecticut Pride Festival, undated
      - Lesbian/Gay Pride Festival Hartford, June 23, 1984
      - Forward Together There's No Stopping Us Now, 1986
      - Don't Hide, 1987
    - New York Pride Festival, undated
      - Don't Try It! '69 Stonewall '89, 1989
      - What a Difference a Gay Makes, 1990
      - Out! Outraged! Outrageous, 1992
    - San Francisco Pride Miscellaneous, undated
      - The Cathedral Project circa 1987/1988, n.d., undated
      - Long Island Act Up, n.d., undated
      - Queer Nation Get Used To It! n.d. Silence = Death, n.d, undated
      - Frontier Disco and Lounge, Springfield, MA, 69ers, undated
      - TARC, Tenderloin AIDS Resource Center, San Francisco, undated
      - Tri-State Area Committee on Lesbian/Gay Issues, undated